DARSHIT GUPTA

Front-End Web Developer

□ darshitgupta777@gmail.com

% https://darshit.js.org

[]+91773717016

https://linkedin.com/in/dg777

Panswara, Rajasthan

Summary

Front-end developer with 1.5+ years of experience in making thoughtful, engaging, and functional web applications with simple, clean, and distinct design using Angular. Also, have experience in database technologies using Oracle SQL with an Oracle Datable SQL Associate certification. Seeking for new opportunities and challenges to further enhance organizational worth by leveraging my skills and knowledge in Front-end development.

Work Experience

Accenture Sol. Pvt Ltd. Angular Developer

Jan 2021 – Current

- Developed and maintained UI for the web application using HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Angular2+.
- Created multiple customizable dashboards with filters that allow users to monitor data in real-time.
- Used chart.js to create visually aesthetic graphs and charts to display consensus data results.
- Implemented Lazy-Loading to decrease the initial loading time for the application.
- Integrated RESTful services (API's) with JSON with SQL Queries for Oracle database.
- Optimized existing application that significantly improved web functionality and UI load time.
- Performed unit testing using Jasmine.

PL/SQL Developer

- Built complex queries using SQL and wrote stored procedures using PL/SQL.
- Involved in updating procedures, functions, triggers, and packages based on the change request.
- Engaged in 100+ hours of training in SQL, PL/SQL, Oracle Forms and Oracle Reports.

Freelance Web Developer

Sept 2020 – Dec 2020

- Designed and developed reusable components and templates with Angular and Firebase supporting multiple web application.
- Assisted in delivering 3+ applications while ensuring high performance on mobile and desktop platforms.
- Interacted with clients to achieve 100% client satisfaction.
- Involved in development of user interface using HTML5, CSS3 and Bootstrap.

Vkreate, Jaipur

May 2019 - July 2019

MEAN Stack Developer - Intern

- Developed a single page ecommerce website.
- Worked on prototype, front-end development, back-end development, and testing.
- Integrated user authentication, payment gateway and admin dashboard.
- Worked with Jasmine for unit testing angular modules.

Technical Skills

Web Technologies:

HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript

Frameworks / Libraries:

Angular, Node.js, TypeScript, Bootstrap, Tailwind

Databases:

SQL, Oracle PL/SQL, Firebase

Programming Languages:

C, C++

Development Tools:

Figma, Adobe Photoshop CS5

Version Control System:

Git

Testing:

Karma, Jasmine

Certifications

- Oracle Database SQL Certified Associate.
- Oracle Cloud Infrastructure Foundations 2021 Associate.
- Front-End JavaScript
 Frameworks: Angular
 from Coursera.
- JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures from Free Code Camp.
- Responsive Web Design from Free Code Camp.

Education

B. Tech, Computer Science

JECRC, Jaipur (RTU) 74.32%

2016 - 2020